<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ModMetaData>
  <name>AS-44 by Wololooo</name>
  <author>wololooo</author>
  <packageId>wololooo.ASFortyFour</packageId>
  <modVersion>1.0.0.0</modVersion>

  <description>The AS-44 is a ghost of a weapon that never truly had its time — a prototype birthed in the chaos of Earth’s bloodiest conflict, forged in desperation, and abandoned before it could shape the future it hinted at.

Developed in the final years of the Second World War on Old Earth — humanity’s cradle, now a burned-out memory scattered among the stars — the AS-44 was the brainchild of Soviet gunsmith Alexey Sudayev. It was among the very first Soviet attempts to create a true assault rifle: select-fire, compact, and chambered in the intermediate 7.62×39mm cartridge. This new round was a revelation — less punishing than full-power battle cartridges, yet far more capable than pistol calibers. The AS-44 was designed to bring mobility and sustained fire into a single soldier’s hands.

But the world was collapsing faster than it could be rebuilt. Only a handful of prototypes were ever produced. Each one was heavy, temperamental, and riddled with experimental mechanisms. The weapon was too ambitious for its time — its complexity outpaced the era’s metallurgy, and Sudayev himself died before refinement could begin. The AS-44 project was shelved, overtaken by simpler, more reliable successors. Its name faded into footnotes, its impact nearly lost to the fires of history.

Yet nothing stays buried forever on the Rim.

Centuries later, long after Earth fell to flame, famine, and silence, fragments of the AS-44’s design were recovered in the memory core of a crashed colonial freighter drifting near a neutron star. Schematics, corrupted but salvageable, were pieced together by a weaponsmith with more will than sense. What emerged was a recreation of the AS-44 — heavy, brutal, and beautiful in its raw, unfinished power.

Now reborn in the hands of desperate Rimworld settlers and scavengers, the AS-44 offers what it always promised: reliable automatic fire, solid mid-range performance, and the spirit of a weapon meant to shape a better future — even if that future never came.

It is clunky. It is rare. It is not perfect. But it works.

A prototype reborn. A future that never was — finally given a second chance among the stars.


~wololooo
</description>
	
  <supportedVersions>
	<li>1.6</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>wololooo.sovietResearchTab</packageId>
      <displayName>Soviet Rifle Research Tab</displayName>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/wo1olooo/Soviet-Rifle-Research-Tab-by-Wololooo</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  
</ModMetaData>
